Before Rambo... Before Oliver North...
Walker is a drama, history, western film directed by Alex Cox.
William Walker and his mercenary corps enter Nicaragua in the middle of the 19th
century in order to install a new government by a coup d'etat.
William Walker, played by Ed Harris.
Ephraim Squier, played by Richard Masur.
Maj. Siegfried Hennington, played by René Auberjonois.
Timothy Crocker, played by Keith Szarabajka.
Captain Hornsby, played by Sy Richardson.
Byron Cole, played by Xander Berkeley.
Walker is a 1987 historical Weird Western film directed by
Alex Cox and written by Rudy Wurlitzer.
It stars Ed Harris as William Walker, the American filibuster who
invaded and made himself president of Nicaragua.
The cast also features Richard Masur, René Auberjonois,
Peter Boyle, Miguel Sandoval and Marlee Matlin.
An American-Mexican co-production, Walker was filmed
in Nicaragua, during the Contra War.
The film is intentionally full of postmodern anachronisms, such as helicopters,
Zippo lighters, automatic rifles, Diet Coke, magazines and cars.
Joe Strummer, formerly of the Clash, scored the film.
Walker was released by Universal Pictures on December 4, 1987 to generally polarized reviews and grossed
nearly $300,000 against a production budget of $6 million, becoming a box-office bomb.
The film explores themes of small town, cannon, sword, mexican standoff, horse.
The tone is emotional.